(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-26T17:46:57.654086",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
本日は、ホロライブファンタジー ファーストライブ「ファンファンアイランド」にご来場いただきまして、
Thank you very much for attending today's Hololive Fantasy 1st Live, "Fan Fan Island,"
誠にありがとうございます。
thank you so very much.
公演を最後まで楽しんでいただくために、皆さまへいくつかのご案内をさせていただきます。
To ensure you enjoy the show to the very end, we would like to share a few notices with everyone.
まず初めに、会場の皆さまへご案内です。
First, an announcement for everyone at the venue.
ロビー客席内では、マスク着用が必須となります。
Wearing a mask is mandatory inside the lobby and seating area.
公演中の声援などは、新型コロナウイルス感染予防の観点からご遠慮ください。
Please refrain from cheering during the performance to prevent the spread of COVID-19.
是非、拍手やペンライトなどでの応援をお願いします。
Please show your support through applause and penlights!
ペンライトは周りのお客さまのご迷惑にならないよう、ご配慮をお願いします。
Please be mindful so that your penlights do not disturb those around you.
頭の上に出したり、大きく左右に振り回すと
Holding them above your head or swinging them wildly
後ろのお客さまや周りのお客さまのご迷惑となる場合がございます。
may cause inconvenience to guests sitting behind or around you.
スタッフが注意させていただく場合がございますので、ご協力ください。
Our staff may caution you if this occurs, so your cooperation is appreciated.
また、会場内では立って応援いただいても問題ありませんが、周りのお客さまのご迷惑にならないよう、ご配慮をお願いいたします。
Also, standing up to cheer is allowed, but please be considerate so as not to disturb those around you.
会場内ではスタッフの指示に従ってください。周りのお客さまにご迷惑をかけるような危険行為はご遠慮ください。
Please follow staff instructions inside the venue and refrain from any dangerous behavior that may inconvenience others.
会場内では携帯電話、スマートフォンはマナーモードに設定をお願いします。
Please set your mobile phones and smartphones to silent mode while inside the venue.
公演中ライブの様子を撮影することは、演出の都合上、禁止といたします。
Recording or photographing the live performance is strictly prohibited for production reasons.
以上のことが守られない場合、安全確保のため、公演を一時中断、もしくは中止させていただくこともございます。
If these rules are not followed, we may temporarily suspend or cancel the performance to ensure everyone's safety.
ご気分のご優れない場合など 何かが御座いましたら お早めに お近くのスタッフにお申し付けください
If you feel unwell or need assistance, please promptly notify a nearby staff member.
また、地震などの緊急時には、スタッフが誘導いたします。スタッフの指示があるまで、お席にてお待ちください。
In the event of an emergency such as an earthquake, staff will guide you. Please remain in your seat until instructed.
また、本公演は映像配信及び写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入るため、お客さまの様子が写り込む場合がございます。
Additionally, cameras for live streaming and photography will be present, so audience members may appear in the footage.
これら映像や写真はプロモーションや今後の活動に使用する可能性がありますので、あらかじめご了解ください。
Please be aware that these images and videos may be used for promotional and future activities.
続いて、配信でご覧の皆さまへの注意事項をお伝えします。
Next, here are some important notes for everyone watching via live stream.
万全の準備を行い、ライブ配信を実施いたしますが、生配信の特性上、不慮の障害で映像の乱れや一時停止などが起こる可能性があります。あらかじめご了解ください。
We will make every preparation for the stream, but due to the nature of live broadcasts, technical issues may cause interruptions or delays. Thank you for your understanding.
本ライブの録音、録画、ミラー配信や違法アップロードは固くお断りいたします。
Recording, filming, mirror streaming, or unauthorized uploading of this live performance is strictly prohibited.
その代わり、スクリーンショットを撮影して画像とともにSNSに投稿していただくことは大歓迎です！
Instead, taking screenshots and sharing them on social media with images is warmly welcomed!
本公演のハッシュタグは、ハッシュタグ「ホロライブ3期生1stライブ」です。
The official hashtag for this concert is #Hololive3rdGen1stLive.
是非ハッシュタグを使ってライブを一緒に盛り上げてください！
Please use the hashtag to enjoy and hype up the live together!
それでは、開演まで今しばらくお待ちください。
Now then, please look forward to the show and wait just a moment longer.
本日は「ホロライブファンタジー 3期生1stライブ FAN FUN ISLAND」にご来場いただきまして、誠にありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for attending Hololive Fantasy 3rd Gen 1st Live FAN FUN ISLAND today.
大変長らくお待たせいたしました。本公演はまもなく開演いたします。
Thank you so much for waiting. This performance will begin shortly.
会場の皆様も、配信でご覧の皆様も、一緒に盛り上がる準備はできてますかー！
Are everyone at the venue and watching the stream ready to get hyped together?!
それではいよいよ開演いたします。「ホロライブファンタジー ファーストライブ ファンファンアイランド」
Without further ado, we will now begin. Hololive Fantasy First Live: FAN FUN ISLAND
スタート！
Start!
よし、じゃあみんな集まったから準備するか。
All right, everyone's gathered, so let's get ready!
えもうちょいゆっくり話そうぺこでしょ。
Wait, shouldn't we talk a bit more slowly, peko?
え、せっかくのライブだよ、こうして久しぶりに5人で集まるとわけわかんない
Eh, it's a special live! Getting all five of us together after so long is crazy—
いやいやいやライブだからこそ準備しなきゃじゃん。
No, no, no! That's exactly why we need to prepare!
そんな勇気でペコラなんか話したいことあんの？
With that attitude, do you even have anything to talk about, Pekora?
あるに決まってるぺこじゃん。
Of course I do, peko!
みなさん？
Minasan?
好きな飲み物なに？
What's your favorite drink?
ええ！？
Huh?!
どういうこと？そんなのライブに関係なくないだろ！しかもライブの控室の飲み物大事ぺこじゃねえの！
What do you mean?! That has nothing to do with the live! And isn't the green room drink super important, peko?!
まあ確かにな。
Well, that's true.
どう？アールグレイティー？
How about Earl Grey tea?
あ、でたでたでたそれ美味しいやつ。
Oh, there it is! That's the delicious one.
あたくしも今日それ。
I'm having that today too.
そうなんだよね、ちょっとルシアからね、今ブームして、うちらこれ全員これ飲んでるからな、だけどもぺこらは飲んでないんだよね？
Yeah, Rushia started it and now all of us are drinking it, but Pekora isn't drinking it, right?
牛乳飲んでるんだよね、ずっとさ。
You've been drinking milk the whole time, peko.
牛乳美味ぺこじゃねえかよ！美味しいけどね。
Isn't milk delicious, peko?! It is delicious, though.
うんうん。
Mm-hmm.
そういえば今日きょきょきょこれ何するんだっけ？きょから泣いてるんだけど！
Come to think of it, what are we doing today again? Why are you crying?!
きょから泣いてるんだけど！
Why are you crying?!
ぺこらをちょっとおいに、え、確かパーティゲームじゃなかったっけ？あそうそうそう会場の参加できるゲーム用意しましたから、
Giving Pekora a hard time—wait, wasn't it a party game? Oh right, we prepared a game everyone at the venue can join,
せっかくのライブだからね歌ったりとかわいわいやりたいじゃないですか？ういちゃーん、楽しそう！
so since it's a live, don't you want to sing and have fun together? Ui-chan looks so happy!
え、でもなんかドキドキしちゃうんだけど大丈夫？
Wait, but I'm feeling kind of nervous, will we be okay?
ちゃんとさ、ちょっとリハーサルとかしとくかん？でも結局さ、やりはじめてみないとわからないからさ、
Shouldn't we do a rehearsal or something? But in the end, we won't know unless we try it out, so—
とりあえずさ、なんか食べながら話さない？どこで今日ペコラやる気ないの？
For now, why don't we talk while eating something? Why aren't you motivated today, Pekora?
確かに！ライブ前の飲み物、そうだよね、ライブと。
True! The drink before the live—that's right, with the live.
もうしょうがないなあ。
Oh well, can't be helped.
ま、でも、これが私たちらしいて言えば、まあ私たちらしいかな？
Well, if this is what makes us us, then I guess it's very us!
確かにな。うっしゃ、オッケー！じゃあ気合づけに、もう早速ね船長たち3期生のライブを祝して！乾杯しようか！
That's true. Alright, okay! Then to pump ourselves up, let's toast to the 3rd Gen's live right away!
あ、いぇい！いぇい！
Yay! Yay!
ノエルお前何食べてんだお前？
Noel, what are you eating?
え？何も食べてないよ。何も食べてない！
Eh? I'm not eating anything. I'm not eating anything!
たまにはに肉が美味しいのです。
Sometimes meat is just so delicious.
ノエルの肉は後でちょ！先に食べるのはおっけ。
Noel's meat can wait! Let's eat what's first, okay?
あれ？誰？声聞こえた？
Huh? Who's that? Did you hear a voice?
誰の声今？なんか聞こえた。
Whose voice was that just now? I heard something.
え、待って、声なんて聞こえた？え、でも声なんて聞こえた？待って待って待って、聞こえてたってこと？
Wait, did you hear a voice? Wait, wait, wait, didn't you hear anything?
ていうかさ、このボードゲームの水晶が光ってない？
Wait, isn't the crystal on this board game glowing?
あ、これね、これ船長がね、これ買ってきたんだわ。
Oh, this? The captain bought this.
え、あ、光ってるわ！光ってる！
Oh, it's glowing! It's glowing!
ちょ、ちょっと待って、なんか引っ張られとる！
Wait, wait, we're being pulled in!
やばい、やばい、やばい！吸い込まれてる！
Oh no, oh no, we're being sucked in!
見つけた。ようやく、彼女たちが
Found them. At last, they have...
そうわすわす止まらないね インタラクティブファンタジア
It never stops, our Interactive Fantasia!
いんたらくときふぁんたじあ きっと ここから消えないセカイ歩いて
Interactive Fantasia, surely walking in a world that won't fade from here
目覚めたファンタジアが動き出す
The awakened Fantasia begins to move
だんだんだんだん目指すは頂点だ ほら付いてくるぺこ
Step by step, aiming for the peak—come follow along, peko!
ちょっと待ってみんなで一緒にね 目の前のことよりも不意の
Wait up everyone, together, rather than what's right in front of us...
怖いものなし 進め イドファイト
Fearless, press forward, Id-fight!
たまには泣いちゃっても負けないもん
Even if we cry sometimes, we won't lose!
明かした秘密を手繰り寄せたら 挑戦の幕が開く
Unspooling our revealed secrets, the curtain of challenge opens
待ちに待って過ぎていく昨日のその目に焼き付け
Waiting so eagerly for yesterday's passing, burning it into our eyes
日が昇る空も 踏み出す大地も
The sky where the sun rises, the ground we step upon
重ね合った 思い出を溢れさせ
Overflowing with overlapping memories
明日へと走り続けよう
Let's keep running toward tomorrow!
果てしない夢を追う まっすぐに
Chasing endless dreams, straight ahead
キミとなら怖くはないから
Because with you, I'm not afraid
戸惑いも全部 その胸に預け愛
Entrusting all hesitation to that chest, love
道なき道も 楽しみながら 走れるよ
We can run even on pathless roads, enjoying every bit
心が今を告げる さあ行くよ
Our hearts announce the present, now let's go!
進むべき未来が待ってる
The future we must advance toward is waiting
半端じゃないキミがいるから
Because you are here, like no other
繋げよう キミとボクの世界 ここから
Let's connect your and my world, starting right here!
いんたらくときふぁんたじあ きっと ここから消えないセカイ歩いて
Interactive Fantasia, surely walking in a world that won't fade from here
目覚めたファンタジアが響くよ
The awakened Fantasia echoes!
前触れなく訪れる日常を 駆け抜くクイックエスケープ
A quick escape running through the everyday that arrives without warning
振り返り バイバイ声上げた ついてこれるよネ ぴんかり
Looking back, saying bye-bye with raised voices, can you keep up, Pinkari?
今かけ出す時は来た
The time to run forth has come!
心の準備はオッケー
Mental preparation is okay!
坂道を鳴らせば 伝説が一歩開く
Ringing up the slope, legend opens by a step
わずかに踏み出した勇気が
The courage we stepped out with just a little bit...
君がいないと 世界は色を失う
Without you, the world loses its color,
おかしいくらい 大袈裟だろう?
isn't it ridiculously exaggerated?
(Now is the time to say)
言葉に出して 気持ちを伝えたいよ
I want to put my feelings into words and tell you,
少し強がりで 健気な君に...
to you, who are a bit stubborn yet brave...
一緒に飛び出してみない？ 届かない夢はない どこででも
Won't you jump out together? There are no unreachable dreams anywhere.
気に入ったなら たどり着くから 叶えたいエールを
If you love it, we'll reach it, so I'll send a cheering shout.
その手元に 握り締め 私の地図を
Clutching it tight in your hands, my map,
描き回して 駆け出そう
draw it out and start running!
願いごとのように歌う 聞こえるよ 幻のファンタジーであっても
Singing like a wish, I can hear it, even in a phantom fantasy.
出会いは幻じゃないなら つなぎよ 君と僕の
If this meeting isn't an illusion, let's connect our story—
この奇跡を 奏で合おう 真実(しんじつ)に
let's play this miracle together into truth.
もっと強くなりたくて
Wanting to become stronger,
ずっと笑い合いたくて
wanting to always laugh together,
いらだつ気持ち 金曜を進んで
pushing through my impatience on Friday,
君と出会ったよ
I met you.
失敗の答えを させるわけないよ
There's no way I'll let failure be the answer,
だっておんなじ毎日
because every single day
楽しすぎたんでしょ？ ドキドキの先の先へ
was too much fun, right? Toward the beyond of heart-pounding thrills,
裸足でかけるけど
running barefoot,
シャカシャカシャカシャカシャカシャカシャカシャカ
shaka-shaka-shaka-shaka...
行こう
let's go.
果てしない夢を
Chasing endless dreams,
まっすぐに君となら 怖くはないから
straight ahead with you, I'm not afraid.
戸惑いも全部 その背中に預け合い 一直線に道も
Entrusting all confusion to each other, going straight down the path,
楽しみながら走れるよ
enjoying ourselves as we run.
ここが「今」を告げる さあ行くよ
Here is what signals "now", come on, let's go,
進むべき未来が待ってる
the future we ought to walk toward is waiting.
他でもない君がいるから
Because you, and no one else, are here,
つなげよう 君と僕の世界 いつまでも
let's connect our world—you and me, forever and ever.
シャカシャカシャカシャカシャカシャカシャカシャカ
shaka-shaka-shaka-shaka...
ここは…？
Where is this...?
Where is this?
海…？
The ocean...?
ていうか、え、ここどこ？
Wait, uh, where even is this?
あ、気がついた？
Ah, you noticed?
うわ、さっきの声！
Whoa, that voice just now!
おお、ようやく来たか！
Oh, you've finally arrived!
全くおセペコ！
You're totally late, Peko!
ノエル、ペコラ…ん？その隣にいるのって…
Noel, Pekora... Hm? Who's that next to you...?
あ、どうも、妖精です。
Ah, hello, I'm a fairy.
は？ いや、だから妖精です。この島の名前は「ミジカ」って言います。
Huh? I mean, like I said, I'm a fairy. This island is called "Mijika".
え？ え？ どういうこと？ ミジカさん、初めまして。
Eh? What does that mean? Mijika-san, nice to meet you.
いやいや、ていうか妖精って…それにどうやってここに？
No, no, I mean a fairy...? Besides, how did we even get here?
まあ、おどろくのも無理ないぺこ。ペコラたちも少し前に起きたんだけど、同じような反応だったからね。
Well, it's only natural to be surprised. We woke up a little while ago and had the exact same reaction.
でね、驚かないで聞いてほしいんじゃけど、なんとここは異世界の無人島なんです！
And listen without freaking out, okay? Believe it or not, this is an uninhabited island in another world!
えーーー！どういうこと！？
Ehhhhh?! What do you mean?!
いやあ、いま流行りの異世界転生って言うんかな？現実とは違う世界に来ちゃったみたいなんだよね。
Well, is this what they call an isekai reincarnation trend? It seems we've ended up in a world different from reality.
そんなファンタジーなことってある？
Can something as fantastical as that even happen?
っていうか私たちが言うのも変なんだけどもさ！
I mean, it's weird for us to say that, but still!
えー、ということはさっきの水晶に引きずり込まれちゃったってことかな？
Eh, so does that mean we got dragged into that crystal from earlier?
そうそう！ それでね、なんかミジカさんからお願いが…
That's right! And also, apparently Mijika-san has a favor to ask—
それよりも、重要なことに気がつかないぺこか？
Before that, haven't you noticed something important, Peko?
え？ 重要なこと？ 妖精、海、と言ったらこれじゃない！
Eh? Something important? Fairy, ocean—if you say that, isn't it this?!
のえちゃん、歌うぺこ！ いやいやいや、いきなり！？
Noe-chan, let's sing, Peko! No no no, all of a sudden?!
派手な夏が胸を刺激する 生足魅惑のマーメイド
A flashy summer stimulates my chest, a bare-legged, captivating mermaid,
露出度高めの mermaid
with high exposure, mermaid,
夏のとこ出して 騒いじゃいなよ
show off the summer side and let's get rowdy!
本物の...
The real...
ごまかしきれない薄着の曲線は
The curves revealed in lightweight clothes
確信犯のしなやかなスタイル
are a calculated, supple style.
体温測定の秒針に切り替わる 瞬間の一瞬の眩しさは逃がさないもの
I won't miss the dazzling flash of the moment
心まで流される 熱い風の誘惑に
Swept away even in my heart by the hot wind.
犯したって構わないから
It doesn't matter if we commit a crime,
真夏は負傷者も 君次第です
so midsummer casualties depend on you.
寄せ付けない夏の刺激する
The stimulating summer that keeps you away,
生足素肌はクロマメイド
bare legs and skin like a black maid.
脱ぐところまで剥けたら
If we can strip down and bare it all,
本物の恋ができそうかい
do you think we can fall in true love?
引けなくてももどき君にもなろう
Even if I can't back down, I'll be like you.
熱い馬鹿の街はユーズド
The hot, foolish town is used.
月を見せたら耳耳に入る 寒気がなくて進みたくない
I don't want to proceed without the chill.
蒸せ返るネタイヤを 色撮る花火のように
Like fireworks coloring the sultry air,
打ち上げて散る思いなら このまま抱き合って焦がれるまで
let's embrace just like this until we scorch.
焦がれるまで
Until we scorch.
寄せ付けた夏の夏を刺激する
Stimulating the summer we brought close,
熱い欲望はトロメイド
hot desires are torrid.
脱ぐもの出して素直になりたい
I want to strip down and be honest,
君と僕と習いズオライ
learning with you and me...
街のビルの海じゃ感じなくなってる君を
You, who no longer feel anything in the city,
誘い出の口づけで弱らせて 届かして
I'll weaken with inviting kisses and make it reach you,
差し上げましょう
and present it to you.
寄せ付けた夏の夏を刺激する
Stimulating the summer we brought close,
生足素肌はクロマメイド
bare legs and skin like a black maid.
恋にがむしゃらでお留守になるのも
Becoming absent-minded and reckless in love
のえぺこ的にもオールOK
is all OK, even for NoePeko style!
寄せ付けない夏の誰としたくなる
Midsummer that keeps you away, who with?
一人での夜に押し寄せる場合
When it surges over you on a lonely night,
奥の方まで乾く暇ないほど
all the way deep, with no time to dry,
本物の恋をしませんか？
won't you fall in true love?
寄せ付けない夏を誰としたくなる
Midsummer that keeps you away, who with?
一人での夜に押し寄せる場合
When it surges over you on a lonely night,
奥の方まで乾く暇ないほど
all the way deep, with no time to dry,
本物の恋をしませんか？
won't you fall in true love?
どうペコ？よかったんだけど、そうじゃなくて、もっと突っ込むとこあるじゃん！
How was it, peko? There are other parts to poke fun at!
いやいや、ふらは今船長めっちゃ黙ってたからね。しかもね、かすかに、お客さんの気持ちがさ、伝わってきた気がする。
Senchou was quiet, and I felt the audience's feelings.
いや、確かに歌ってたら、ライブ会場のような不思議な感覚がしたぺこ。
Yeah, I got a strange feeling like we were at a live venue.
うん！そしたら船長の歌しかないでしょ！ええー！？
Yeah! Then it has to be Senchou's song! Eh?!
いやいや、もう君たち、いるなら手拍子やコメントで愛の手を入れて存在をアピールしてください！
Please clap or comment to show your love and presence!
あほい！我ら宝鐘海賊団、しゅこー！
Ahoy! We are the Houshou Pirates, dispatch!
や、よしろう。あ、よしろう。あ、よしろう。庭にはやめて庭に。
Hey, Yoshirou. Stop in the yard.
海賊なら yo-ho! 踊れ 叫べ yo-ho!
If you're a pirate, yo-ho! Dance and shout, yo-ho!
さあ 今 旗 の もと へ (hi hi hi hi ohhhhh)
Now, gather under the flag!
宝鐘海賊団 出航～！
Houshou Pirates, set sail~!
踊る ahoy! に 見る ahoy! （ ホイホイ ！ ）
Dancing ahoy! Come see ahoy! (hoi hoi!)
（ ahoy! ahoy! ahoy! ホイホイ ホーイ ！ ）
(ahoy! ahoy! ahoy! hoi hoi hoii!)
全速前進だ ～ ！
Full speed ahead~!
進め ！ （ 進め ！ ）
Sail forward! (Sail forward!)
太陽 は サンサン 大航海 日和 だ
The sun is shining bright, a fine day for a voyage!
歌え ！ （ 歌え ！ ）
Sing! (Sing!)
最高 の テンション 波 の 音 に 乗せ て ドンブラコ
Riding on the churning waves with the best mood,
海 で ガールズ party 陸 で 兄貴 が happy
On the sea it's a girls' party, on land the big bro is happy!
お空ではドクロくんヒラヒラ
In the sky, skull-kun flutters,
山奥ボロボロマイハウスで夢を見て
dreaming in my rundown mountain shack.
「 あん 、 神様 ぁ ！ いつか この マリン を 本物 の 海賊 に ． ． ． し て くだんたぁ ～ い 」
"Dear God! Someday, please make this Marine a real pirate...!"
はっ 神様 いつかこのマリンを本物の海賊にしてください！
Ah, God, please make this Marine a real pirate someday!
声を上げてさあ出港だ
Raise your voices, set sail now!
我ら保証海賊団
We are the Houshou Pirates!
コンパス片手に旗を上げ この海をジャックしちゃおう
With a compass in hand, raise the flag and jack this sea!
夜空すいいておいで共にいよ 夜空へ叫ぼう ああ
Swoop down from the night sky, come together, shout to the night sky, ah!
最高の日々
The best days!
夜更こうまで笑え舟へ
Laugh until late at night, onto the ship!
踊れあほい 見るあほい
Dance, ahoy! Watch, ahoy!
1, 2, 3番サンバ 熱く
1, 2, 3-ban Samba, passionately
語れよファッション 思いを解き放て
Talk about fashion, unleash your feelings!
赤く煌めくファッション 形から入るタイプです
Glowing in bright red fashion, I'm the type who enters from the appearance!
発射準備まえ 走れ 勝ち取りれっしゅ
Before launch preparation, run, win and take it
揺れても手れるわ キラキラ
Even trembling will shine, glittering...
じんわり汗も滴るいい女 だけど
A fine woman with sweat gently dripping, but...
はっ 神様 船長はセンシティブだとバンされちゃうのですね はにゃーん
Ah, God, if the captain is too sensitive, she'll get banned, right? Hanyaan!
奪われたら取り戻せ それが保証海賊団
If it's taken away, take it back, that's the Houshou Pirates!
キミ達となら辿り着ける 伝説のエルフ
If it's with you guys, we can reach the legendary elf!
夜空楽しきゃ歌おう 夜空は足りない ああ
If the night sky is fun, let's sing, the night sky is not enough, ah!
この景色
This scenery!
大切な仲間よ
Precious comrades!
騒げや騒げ 踊れあほい 見るあほい
Make some noise, dance, ahoy! Watch, ahoy!
同じアホなら飲まなきゃ損々
If we're both fools, it's a loss not to drink!
逆さたる片手に一気まっしぐら それあほい あほい
Headfirst with a barrel in hand straight ahead, that's ahoy, ahoy!
保証マリオ？保証マリン
Houshou Mario? Houshou Marine!
世界で一番可愛いよ
The cutest in the world!
滅が鬼滅が 鬼滅は鬼滅が エロが消えろが
Destruction is Kimetsu? Kimetsu is Kimetsu? Ecchi is disappearing?
ボンキュッボン お嬢ちゃんパンツの色？
Bon-kyu-bon! Young lady, what color are your panties?
お宝 お宝 戻い 戻い
Treasure, treasure, bring it back, bring it back!
何でもスドン 船長のちっちゃいとこ
Anything goes, the Captain's tiny spot!
タクシーに 違反マイキング
Taxi, violating biking!
脱中の セビサビチュー
Stripping inside, s-s-sabichuu!
萌え萌えきゅん 出会って5秒で
Moe moe kyun, 5 seconds after meeting!
もう 船長は君たちをそんな風に育てた覚えはありません！本当にねぇ、たぞ？
Jeez, Captain doesn't remember raising you guys like that! Really, right?
立てばジジョ 座るジジョ 歩く姿はセンシティブ
Sitting posture, standing posture, walking figure is sensitive!
夢も見ようこの船で 後悔なんてさせない
Let's dream on this ship too, we won't let you regret it!
キミ達のおかげで私は船長になれるから
Thanks to you guys, I can become the captain!
開けろ船長さーん 打て！
Open up, Captain! Fire!
声を上げてさあ出港だ
Raise your voices, set sail now!
我ら保証海賊団
We are the Houshou Pirates!
コンパス片手に旗を上げ この海をジャックしちゃおう
With compass in hand, raise the flag and jack this sea!
夜空すいいておいで共にいよ 夜空へ叫ぼう ああ
Swoop down from the night sky, come together, shout to the night sky, ah!
最高の日々
The best days!
夜更こうまで笑え舟へ
Laugh until late at night, onto the ship!
ほうしょうの 海賊だ
The Houshou pirates!
それではいきますよ シュカー
Now then, here we go! Shuu--kaa!
ねー！すごかったねー！
Hey! That was amazing!
あ、どーもどーも、いやね、ちょっとやっぱ分かった。やっぱりこれねリスナーさん、間違いなくいるぞ。
Ah, hello hello, well, you know, I finally got it. As expected, listeners are definitely here.
感じた。みんなも歌ったほうがいい。まじか！
I felt it. Everyone should sing too. Seriously?!
なるほど。とりあえずみんなで一緒に歌って状況整理しようってことかな？
I see. So basically, we should all sing together and sort out the situation?
え！？そんな狙い？うそ！ふでよ、ノエル、一緒に歌おう。
Eh?! Is that the goal? No way! Fudeyo, Noel, let's sing together.
え、ちょっと待って、団長2回目なんだけど！いくよ！えーーー！
Eh, wait a minute, this is the Commander's second time! Here we go! Eeeeeh!
パッとパッと華やかに 咲かせましょう 花のように
Blooming brilliantly and brightly, like flowers!
花咲く、はい、いらっしゃる、はいには
Blooming flowers, yes, coming, yes to...
星のは 少しの、を踏み出す
Stars of a little bit, stepping forward...
空音 撫でる為に
To caress the empty sound,
薄荷の花に誓って
swearing by the mint flower,
唐紅の嘘を重ねたの
piling up crimson lies.
唯の一つでいいの
Just one is fine,
約束を教えて
tell me the promise.
容姿の無い この思索の庭 木々の奥深く
In this formless garden of contemplation, deep within the trees,
ぱっと花咲け 艶やかに 咲かす様に
burst into bloom, brilliantly, as if blossoming.
ひらり、ありふれて情緒 刹那 晴れやかに
Fluttering, commonplace emotion, fleeting and radiant,
境界なんて曖昧でしょう
boundaries are ambiguous, aren't they?
光浴びながら煌めけ いつか雨上がり 末代まで
Bathed in light, sparkle, someday after the rain, until the end of generations,
呪いかけて 祭り騒ぎ
cast a curse, make a festive uproar!
待っては掛けられないと
Saying we can't wait or hang back,
抗えないと 老いを重ねたの
unable to resist, piling up old age.
参差の御伽も ほらね、信じるのでしよ
Even jagged fairy tales, look, you believe them, right?
中昧は 有象無象の葬列 無数の火玉を連れて
The inside is a procession of all sorts, leading countless fireballs.
ぱっと切り裂け 派手に飛沫を上げて
Burst and tear through, raising a flamboyant splash,
僕の命は生生世世 生かすも地獄 殺すも地獄
my life is through all eternity—living is hell, killing is hell.
御前の命を惜しむないか 月夜が満ちる
Won't you spare your life? The moonlit night fills up.
ひらり、ありふれて情緒 刹那 晴れやかに
Fluttering, commonplace emotion, fleeting and radiant,
境界なんてなんて曖昧でしょう
boundaries are so ambiguous, aren't they?
光浴びながら煌めけ いつか雨上がり 末代まで
Bathed in light, sparkle, someday after the rain, until the end of generations,
呪いかけて 祭り騒ぎ
cast a curse, make a festive uproar!
まっさらな絵を描いて 何時何時までも夢を見ていたの まだ一人で眠る
Drawing a pristine picture, dreaming forever and ever, still sleeping alone.
踊れや踊れ
Dance and dance,
散らさないで
don't scatter away!
もっともっと一緒に数えたい 新しい景色
More and more, I want to count new scenery together with you.
色葉にほぱっとぱっと晴れやかに
In colorful leaves, burst and bloom brilliantly,
咲かせましょう 花のように これからの君が見たい
let's make them bloom like flowers, I want to see you from now on.
色葉にほぱっとぱっと晴れやかに
In colorful leaves, burst and bloom brilliantly,
咲かせる想いはつね習う
the feelings that bloom are always learned—
だって乙女道は風任せだと
because a maiden's path is left to the wind,
呟いてみた
I murmured to myself.
乙女ごころさ 迷ってるだけなら何も起こらない
A maiden's heart—if you're just hesitating, nothing will happen.
強気でいくんだと 瞳で語るよ
Speaking with your eyes that you'll go on strong.
そしたらさ おいで 明日がピカピカと
Then come on over, tomorrow sparkles brightly,
輝く夢の 色に変わる
turning into the color of a shining dream.
歌えや歌え 浮かかれながら
Sing and sing, while getting carried away,
ずっとずっと一緒に遊びたい
I want to play together forever and ever,
桜色ハーモニー 散り急ぐをおさっさとながれてく
cherry blossom harmony, flowing swiftly away as it falls...
イェーイ！イェーイ！やったー！
Yay! Yay! We did it!
この歌、この気持ち、このお客さんみんなの反応……
This song, this feeling, the reaction of everyone in the audience...
やっぱり、ボクは間違ってなかった！
I was right after all!
え？
Eh?
え？あ、ていうか、確かに歌うことにお客さんの気配を感じるんだけど、
Eh? Ah, I mean, I certainly sense the audience's presence when singing, but...
この島は音楽とそれを楽しむ気持ちこそが力の源泉になっているんだ。
this island's source of power is music and the joy of enjoying it.
今までの歌を聴いて、そして見ているお客さんのワクワクする心を 感じて確信したよ。この世界を救うために君たちの、
Listening to past songs and feeling the excitement of the audience watching, I'm convinced. To save this world, your...
そしてこのライブを見ている皆さんの力を貸してください！
and everyone watching this live—please lend us your power!
るーしー！
Rushia!
うん、助けてあげたい気持ちはもちろんあるんだけどさ、だったらちょっとライブ会場でお客さんも待ってるし、例えば一度元の世界に返してもらってからとかでもいい？
Yeah, of course we want to help, but in that case, since the audience is waiting at the live venue, for example, could you send us back to our original world once first?
それが……この世界にみんなを呼ぶのに最後の力を使い出しちゃって……
The thing is... I used up my last bit of power to summon everyone to this world...
ええっ！？
Eh?!
じゃあどうしたらいいの？巻き込んじゃってごめんなさい！
Then what should we do? I'm sorry for dragging you into this!
でも、この島の様子はみんなにもこうやって伝わ――
But, the state of this island is being conveyed to everyone like th—
もし、この島の力を取り戻せたら、みんなのことはちゃんと元の世界に戻せるから。
"If we can restore this island's power, we can properly return everyone to their original world."
みちかちゃん、謝らないで。
"Michika-chan, don't apologize."
まあ、そういうことならしょうがないでしょ。
"Well, if that's how it is, it can't be helped."
うん、無人島探索しかも異世界だからね。
"Yeah, exploring an uninhabited island, and in another world at that."
せっかくなら楽しむしかないっしょ。
"Since we're here, we might as well enjoy it."
まあ、確かにある意味夢のような経験ではあるしね。
"Well, it is, in a way, like a dream-like experience."
会場のみんなも配信で見てるみんなも、いっペコか？
"Everyone at the venue, and everyone watching the stream, are you ready peko?"
ペコラたちは今異世界にいるんだけど、みんなのことはしっかり見えてるよ。
"Pekora and the others are in another world right now, but we can see you all clearly."
みんなが楽しむ気持ちも必要だから、ちゃんと盛り上がってペコね！
"Everyone's feeling of enjoyment is needed too, so make sure to get hyped, peko!"
イェーイ！
"Yeah!"
みんな、ありがとう！
"Everyone, thank you!"
でも、具体的には何すればいいんだろうか？
"But specifically, what should we do?"
まずはそのあたりを説明するね。でも、いつまでも海辺だとあれだから、いったん森の方に移動しながらにしよう。
"First, I'll explain about that. But since staying at the beach forever is awkward, let's move toward the forest while we do."
うん、そうしようか。
"Yeah, let's do that."
森か……久しぶりだな。
"A forest... It's been a while."
あ、そっか。エルフ、エルフの森は無人島じゃないもんな。
"Ah, right. An elf... the elf forest isn't an uninhabited island, after all."
無人島だって言ってるじゃん。無人島だけど無人島じゃないの。
"I keep saying it's an uninhabited island. It's uninhabited, but not uninhabited."
無料視聴の方々はここまでになるので、続きは良ければチケットを買って楽しんでね。みんなの力も必要になるから、ぜひよろしくお願いします。
"For those watching the free preview, this is where it ends. If you'd like to see the rest, please buy a ticket and enjoy! We'll need everyone's help too, so we appreciate your support."
ん？何か言った？
"Hm? Did you say something?"
ううん。
"Nope."
じゃあ、さっそく行こう！
"Well then, let's go!"
イェーイ！
"Yeah!"
楽しみだな！楽しもう！めっちゃ楽しみだな！のいちゃおうかな。
"I'm looking forward to it! Let's enjoy it! I'm so excited! Shall we get going?"